Patricia Masigla

5112 Hollywood Rd • College Park, Maryland • 20740 • **CELL:** (732) 754 4246 • **EMAIL:** patricia.masigla@gmail.com **Website:** http://pbmasigla.github.io/

Goals

To develop, strengthen, and build skills in all parts of the information technology field; I would like to parttake in more parts of the software development cycle, such as planning, analyzing, and testing projects and code.

To gain exposure to project management experience in order to successfully deploy products and releases; to see how project managers interact with other teams and divisions for completing large tasks.

Education

University of Maryland - College Park Expected Graduation: May 2015

College of Behavioral and Social Sciences - B.A. Economics; Minor: Business Analytics; GPA: 3.2

Known Programs/Languages/CMSs/IDEs

Languages-> Java, Javascript, Visual Basic, PHP, HTML, CSS, XML

Programs-> Eclipse, IntelliJ, Sublime Text, Putty, Github

CMSs-> Wordpress, Drupal, ExpressionEngine

Media Programs-> Adobe Premier Pro, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Final Cut Pro X, iMovie, Microsoft Office Collection

Experience

Division of Student Affairs - Web Developer | September 2013 - Present

Given the responsibility of managing the main website of the Division of Student Affairs at the University of Maryland at http://www.sagiving.umd.edu/Giving/; using HTML, CSS and PHP to create an organized and intuitive website for donations; currently developing a content management system that will allow web updates even by non-IT members of the team.

Dow Jones and Company - Information Technology Blogs Team Intern | Summer 2013

Created and maintained the Wall Street Journal blogs at http://blogs.wsj.com/ as a technical intern for the WSJ blog's team using the Wordpress platform while incorporating HTML, PHP, and XML skills; used XML and DTD skills for Quality Assurance to solve errors in the back end portion of the blog content-management system.

Filipino Cultural Association - Webmaster | May 2012 - January 2013

Maintained http://www.fcaatumd.com/ website and was tasked at implementing regular content updates related to the organization's activities, announcements and other web contents; used web development skills to create new web pages for events and content needs; used video editing tools for these webpages and for announcements.

TechChange - Web Developer | Summer 2012

Worked on web development for http://www.techchange.org/ using PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, GitHub on the WordPress platform; analyzed the code for functions that needed improvement and formed blueprints in order to execute and push changes.

Filipino Cultural Association - Freshman Representative | October 2011 - May 2012

Planned and spearheaded team-building activities and large-scale events for the freshman class and the entire General Body members; gained leadership, communication and organizational skills through various tasks and responsibilities as an Executive Board Member.

Kumon - Assistant Instructor | March 2010 - August 2011

Developed an informational static content website using HTML and CSS for Kumon of Jamesburg; worked as the right hand of Head Instructor/owner and ensured that the learning center ran smoothly on a daily basis; obtained problem-solving, organizational skills, and people skills from all the daily interactions and exposure to daily operations and challenges in the learning center.